Guide to the Yale University Art, Architecture, and Art History Theses and Projects
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Theses and research papers, 1934, 1943-1977; Series III
  - Bowles, Edmund A. Burgundian Art at the Ducal Court (1363-1467). M.A. (HA) 132 p., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Brett-Smith, Sarah Catherine. Bokolanfini Signs: Their Origin and Significance. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 163 p., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
  - Brilliant, Richard. A New Look at the Ara Pacis Augustae. M.A. (HA) 48 p., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Brooks, H. Allen, Jr.,. Leopold Eidlitz (1823-1908) M.A. (HA) 37 p., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Brown, Aimée Bertha,. Vorticism: Manifestoes and Manifestations, 1912-1917. Vol. I & II M.A. (HA) 242 p., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28-31)
  - Brown, David A.,. Uccello's Battle-pieces for the Medici Palace. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 190 p., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 32-34)
  - Brown, Elizabeth Mills,. The Architects of Center Church, New Haven, Connecticut. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 196 p., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 35-37)
  - Brown, Jack Perry. The Duesseldorf School and American Painting, 1850-1865. Dept. Paper. (HA) 56 p., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Brown, Marilyn R. Uccello's Pictorial Space. M.A. (HA) 149 p., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
  - Bruzelius, Caroline A.,. Central Plan Churches and Chapels in Romanesque France. 125 p., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Bunnell, Peter. The Critical Decade: A Study of the Photography of England and America between the Two London Exhibitions of 1851 and 1862. Vol, I & II M.A.(HA) 130 p, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 42-43)
  - Cameron, John B. The Early Gothic Screenwall. M.A. (HA) 94 p., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Cameron, Vivian P. An Ivory Relief in the Trier Cathedral Treasury. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 131 p., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
  - Camfield, William Arnett. "La Section d"Or". M.A. (HA) 154 p., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Campus Philippe F. An Inquiry into a Research Method of Cognition Processes of Architectural Spaces. M.E.D., 137 p., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Carlson Eric Gustav. Religious Architecture in Normandy 911-1000. Vol. I.&II. M.A. (HA) 159 p., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 49-50)
  - Carroll Richard. Restoration Department, Studies.7 p., 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Carroll S.C. Retail Center Waterbury. B. Arch., 1943
    See: box 3, folder 5
  - Castaneda Hernan. Farmer's Market and the Integral Needs of Infrastructure of Commercialization for Metropolitan Area of Lima. Vol. I & II. M.C.P. 247 p., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 52-54)
  - Casteras, Susan P. Susan MacDowell Eakins: 1851-1938. M.A. (HA) 60 p., 1973 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Chafee, Richard S. Edward Tuckerman Potter and Mark Twain: An Architect and His Client. Vol. I.& II. M A. (HA) 168 p., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 56-57)
  - Chermayeff, Serge and Tzonis, Alexander. Advanced Studies in Urban Environments: Toward an Urban Model. Study by Master Class in Architecture. 206 p., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Clark Mary Jane. "Twin Pines and Level Distance". A Landscape Painting by Chao Meng-Fu. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 128 p., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 59-60)
  - Clarke John R. The Portrait Iconography of Germanicus and Drusus the Younger. Vol. I-III. Dept. Paper (HA) 124 p., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 61-64)
  - Coe, Ralph T. The Rockefeller Building by Knox and Elliot: A Document of Louis Sullivan's Influence in Cleveland, Ohio. M.A. (HA) 60 p., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Cohen, Harriet. Decision-making in Urban Renewal. A Case Study in Citizen Participation. M.C.P. 113 p., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Collins Bradford R. Jr. Studies in Manet Iconography of the 1860"s. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper (HA) 127 p., 1969
    See: box 2, folders 1-2
  - Cousins Robert H. A Tri-state Scenic Road. M.C.F. 64 p., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Cutler John B. Sachem's Wood: An Early Example of the Greek Revival in American Domestic Architecture. Vol. I & II., 1963
    See: box 4, folders 6-7
  - Dant Noel. A Physical Plan for the New Haven Sub-urban Region, Conn. M. Arch 380 p., 1946
    See: box 2, folder 3
  - Davis E. Fletcher. Variables Affecting Mass Transit Usage. M.C.P. 38 p., 1958 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Davis, Sam. Study on Architecture Education and Yale Masters of Architecture Curriculum Proposal. M.E.D. 36 p., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Davison Mary C. Isaia Da Pisa and Roman Aesthetic Ideals of the Quattrocento. M.A. (HA) 134 p., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 70-71)
  - Del Gais Deborah. The Problem of the Sanguszko Tent. Dept. Paper. (HA) 79 p., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - D'Oench Ellen Gates. Arthur Davis, the Early Years. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 125 p., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 73-74)
  - Donnelly Marion Card. New England Meeting Houses in the 17th Century. Vol. I-III. Ph.D.? p., 1956 (Box 6, Folder 75-77)
  - Drapeau Jeanne. The Great Cross of Abbot Suger at Saint-Denis. M.A. (HA) 64 p., 1958 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Druick Douglas W. Cézanne, Vollard, and Lithography: The Ottawa Maquette for the "Large Bathers" Colour Lithograph. (HA) - In Lieu of Masters Paper for Advanced Study., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Duemling Robert Werner. House Planning in the Picturesque Period: England and America, 1790-1840. M.A. (HA) 119 p., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Duncan Arthur. The Political Economy of Urban Development. Part I & II. M.E.D. 107 p., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 81-82)
  - Edelstein Harvey. Coming Together: An Information and Communication Service for the Hill Community. Thesis(?) 13 p., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Eisler Colin. The Steiglitz Circle. Scholar of the House Program. 570 p., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 84-86)
  - Evenson, Norma. Chandigarh: A Study of the Initial Plan of the Capital of East Punjab India. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 119 p., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 87-88)
  - Faghih Nasrine. Isfahan: Continuity of Tradition. Structure of the Medieval Islamic City. M.E.D. 50 p., 1974(?) (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Falkenheim Jacqueline V. Julius Meier-Graefe on Cézanne: A German Contribution to the Understanding of French Art. Dept. Paper. (HA) 107 p., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Fehm Sherwood Anthony Jr. An Essay in the Study of Sienese Painting 1315-1335: The Master of Citta Di Castello. M.A. (HA) 100 p., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Foss W. Perkins. Urhobo Wood Sculpture. Vol. I.& II. M.A. (HA) 126 p., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 92-94)
  - Foster Philip Ellis. The Date of Lorenzo de" Medici's Villa at Poggio a Caiano. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 267 p., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 95-97)
  - Freeman Milly. The Relationship of Philippe de Champaigne to Port-Royal Jansenism M.A. (HA) 128 p., 1964 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Gangneux Marie-Christine. Pullman City in Relation to Industrial Space. Vol. I & II. Thesis(?) 178 p., 1972 (Box 7, Folder 99-100)
  - Gerba John, Jr. Land Allocation and Activity Assignment in Urban Areas. M.C.P. 126 p., 1961
    See: box 2, folder 4
  - Gerhart Charles James. Present Day Books - With Special Emphasis on Book Illustrations and Their Relation to the Text. B.P.A. 17 p., 1952 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Glick Ruth Galanter. A Humanist View of Social Planning. M.C.P. 45 p., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Goglia Margaret R. Physical Environment - Organization Dynamics. M.E.D. 94 p., 1975 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Golden Kenneth. Downtown Renewal: The New Haven Experience. M.C.P. 51 p., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Gordon Jeffrey N. Internal Shopping Circulation at a Regional Shopping Center. M.C.P. 50 p., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Grace Lucy M. Picturesque Theory and English Landscape Painting of the Late Eighteenth and Early Nineteenth Centuries. Dept. Paper. (HA) 131 p., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Graham Duncan M. The Town of Milford in the Bridgeport New Haven Region. M.C.P. 43 p., 1955 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Granady James T. Jr. The Poster as an Element of Urban Living. Vol. I. M.F.A. - p. [Illustrations missing], 1956 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Grilli Stephanie. Bouguereau: The "Perfect" Painter. Vol. I & II. M.A. 193 p., 1974 (Box 7, Folder 109-111)
  - Guerin Francois. Form, Order, and Design. M.E.D. 113 p., 1973 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Gyongy Adrienne. An Iconographic Study of the First Three Representations of the "Triumph" of St. Thomas Aquinas in Tuscan Painting of the 14th Century. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 78 p., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 113-114)
  - Hamilton George Heard. Hezekiah Augur: An American Sculptor, 1791-1858. M.A. (HA) 185 p., 1934 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Hart John. Teaching Space Concepts to Primary School Children. M.E.D. 131 p., 1974 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Henderson Linda Dalrymple. A New Facet of Cubism: "The Fourth Dimension" and "Non-Euclidean Geometry" Reinterpreted. Dept. Paper. (HA) 45 p., 1971 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Herbert Robert Louis. Seurat and the Science of Symbolism. M.A. (HA) 65 p., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Hersey George L. The Arch of Alfonso in Naples: The Growth of its Style and Imagery. Vol. I. M.A. (HA) 98 p. [Vol. II missing], 1961 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Hess Carolyn Elizabeth. Location of the Elderly in the State of Connecticut. M.C.P. 34 p., 1959 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Heyman Therese T. Godefroid of Huy: "Aurifaber". M.A. (HA) 77 p., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Hills John B. A Study of Four Florentine Cassone Panels of the Fifteenth Century at Yale University. M.A. (HA) 37 p., 1950 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Hinson Mary Alice Dixon. Godey's Lady's Book: Associationism and Anthropomorphism in American Domestic Architecture, 1837-1877. M.A. (HA) 140 p., 1976 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Hoag, John D. Jacopo Bellini and the Antique. M.A. (HA) 90 p., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Homer, Lauren. Public Services and Public Facilities: A Systems Approach to Analysis and Simulation. M.C.P. 50 p., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Horn Hendrik J. Honoré Bonet's Arbre des Batailles and Jacques. de Valère"s Traité de Noblesse: A Late Fifteenth Century, Flemish Manuscript in the Yale University Library. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper. 168 p., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 126-128)
  - Hough, John. An Investigation Into a method of Design [For photographs See Box VIII oversize], 1957 (Box 8, Folder 128a)
  - Hufnagel Karen and Votava Bob. Play in the City. M.C.P. 123 p. (2 copies), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 129-130)
  - Huntington David Carew. Oriental Influences on Frank Lloyd Wright. M.A. (HA) 211 p., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 131-132)
  - Irving Robert Grant. The Fitzwilliam Museum, Cambridge University. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper. 165 p., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 133-134)
  - Ishii Kazuhiro. Possibilities in Intentional Regression. M.E.D. 106 p., undated (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - Jacobus John M. Jr. The Architectural Philosophy of Viollet-Le-Duc. M.A. (HA) 62 p., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - Janson Ellen Gutsche. Edwin Austin Abbey's Illustrations to Dickens' Christmas Stories, 1875. M.A. (HA) 113 p., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Janson Richard H. Trinity Church on the New Haven Green. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 95 p., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 138-139)
  - Johnson Kenny. The Political Context of Planning: An Introduction to the Problem. M.C.P. 49 p., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - Jost Mary Louise. The Sarcophagus of Junius Bassus, A Study of 14th Century Christian Relief and Iconography. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 117 p., 1965 (Box 9, Folder 141-142)
  - Kaplan Barry A. Bursae Eleganter Gemmatae: The History of an Abandoned Liturgical Implement. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper (HA) 82 p., 1972 (Box 9, Folder 143-144)
  - Keach Gloria. Two Flemish Manuscripts of Caesar's Commentaries. Dept. Paper (HA) 82 p., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Keefe John Webster. The Setting of the Designs for the Philadelphia City Hall and Its Building History Through the Laying of the Cornerstone, July 4, 1874. Vol. I & II, M.A. (HA) 142 p., 1965 (Box 9, Folder 146-147)
  - Kertess Klaus. Heinrich Campendonk: His Work from 1905 to 1925. M.A. (HA) 117 p., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - Koplin Norma-Jean. Portrait Drawing with Reference to Hans Holbein. B.F.A. 42 p., 1967
    See: box 5, folders 9-10
  - Kostof Spiro K. Attic Dimorphic Vases. M.A. (HA) 96 p., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 149)
  - Kowalski Jeff Karl. The Iconography of the Architectural Sculpture of the Palace of the Governor at Uxmal. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 177 p., 1975 (Box 9, Folder 150-151)
  - Kuehn Robert H. Jr. Housing Cost Analysis Study. Vol. I & II. M.U.S. 214 p., 1968
    See: box 6, folder 13
  - Langsam Walter E. The New York State Capitol at Albany: Evolution of the Design, 1866-1876. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 170 p., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 152-153)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The author has given permission for reproduction in perpetuity.
  - Lawder Standish D. The Structure of the Inner Lining in Churches of Dominikus Zimmerman. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 181 p., 1962 (Box 10, Folder 154-155)
  - Lehman Arnold. Paul Ranson (1860-1905): A Biography. Dept. Paper. (HA) 108 p., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 156)
  - Leider Charles Luedtke Gerald and Werner Constance. Historic Preservation Study, Guilford, Connecticut. Essay, Dept. City Planning. 66 p., 1964 (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Levine Neil A. The Idea of Frank Furness" Buildings. M.A. (HA) 115 p., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - Lewis C. D. The Image of Greece in Eighteenth Century English Architecture. M.A. (HA) 121 p., 1963 (Box 10, Folder 159-160)
  - Litfin Gavin Henry. Central City Renewal: The U.S. Experience 1949-1976. M.E.D. 301 p. (Box 10, Folder 161-162)
  - Lockwood George F. Motion and Time. B.F.A., 1956
    See: box 4, folder 8
  - Loope Ryc. Energy Use and Strategy in the Built Environment. M.A. Thesis Draft. 315 p., 1977? (Box 10, Folder 163-164)
  - Lowic Lawrence. Francesco Di Giorgio: A Study of His Theory of Secular Building Design. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper.(HA) 81 p., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 165-166)
  - Lukosius Richard B. The Nature of an Art Education with Respect to Painting. M.F.A. 22 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - McCormick Gene E. Fitz Hugh Lane: Gloucester Artist, 1804-1865. M.A. (HA) 111 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 168)
  - McGraw Patricia. An Italianate Glazed Terra Cotta Bust in the Yale University Art Gallery. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 98 p., 1954 (Box 10, Folder 169-170)
  - Makzoumi Jala. Some Aspects of the Urbanization Process in Iraq. M.E.D. 144 p., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 171)
  - Mancusi-Ungaro Harold R. Jr. Michelangelo: The Bruges Madonna and the Piccolomini Altar. Scholar-of-the-House Program. 283 p., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - Manice Hayward F. Financial Analysis of Proposed Yale University Shopping Center. B.A. (Arch.) 7 p., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Manley Douglas R. Redevelopment Study—East Side Commercial Area, Middletown, Connecticut. Research Project, City Planning. 17 p., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Manner Helen M. The Romanesque Architecture of Viterbo (text only). Dept. Paper. (HA) 98 p. ILLUSTRATIONS ARE AVAILABLE ON THE FILM HM 206, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - Marlow Peter O. Jacques Saly's Suite de Vases. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 133 p., 1966 (Box 11, Folder 176-177)
  - Matela Raymond. An Analysis of the Animals of Architecture: A Complete Enumeration of Polyominoes by Some of Their Architectural Properties. M.E.D. 101 p., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 178-180)
  - Maxfield William Heyward. The Development of a Geographic Reference File and Its Use in Planning and Evaluation Studies. M.C.P. 54 p., 1972 (Box 11, Folder 181)
  - Maytham Thomas N. Seventeenth-Century Architectural Style in Milford, Connecticut. M.A. (HA) 103 p., 1956 (Box 11, Folder 182-183)
  - Mead Walter L., Jr. Optical Mixture and its Use in the Creation of Form and Space. B.F.A. 29 p., 1956 (Box 11, Folder 184)
  - Meeks C. L. V. Architectural Criticism in America 1864-1929. M.A. 135 p., 1934 (Box 11, Folder 185)
  - Meusel Louise. Children and Construction=Cubes and Cognition. M.E.D. 95 p., 1973 (Box 11, Folder 186)
  - Miles Ellen G. (nee Gross). The Influence of John Smibert's Dean Berkeley and His Entourage on American Colonial Group Portraiture, 1740-1776. Dept. Paper (HA) 93 p., 1968 (Box 11, Folder 187-188)
  - Miller Meredith. Residential Planning Areas for New Haven. M.C.P. 331 p. (2 copies), 1961 (Box 11, Folder 189-190)
  - Mitchell William Edwin. Lithographs by Oskar Kokoschka: 1907-1914. M.A. (HA) 64 p., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 191)
  - Mochon Anne. August Macke and Robert Delauney: Color and Light in Painting, 1912-1914. Dept. Paper (HA) 98 p., 1968 (Box 11, Folder 192)
  - Moore Sandra V. Experiencing Architecture. M.E.D. 132 p., 1973 (Box 12, Folder 193)
  - Muller Jeffrey. Edward Norgate's Miniatura or the Art of Limning. Dept. Paper (HA) 112 p., 1972 (Box 12, Folder 194)
  - Murdock Robert Mead. Elements of Style and Iconography in the Work of Roger de la Fresnaye, 1910-1914. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 124 p., 1965 (Box 12, Folder 195-196)
  - Neill Mary. The Landscape Paintings of Tung Ch"i-Ch"ang (1555-1636): An Album of Eight Landscapes dated 1630. Dept. Paper (HA) 84 p., 1971 (Box 12, Folder 197)
  - Nesbit Margaret S. Atget's Book, L'Artdans le Vieux Paris: Tradition and the Individual Photographic Talent. M.A. (HA) 121 p., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 198)
  - Nilson George. The University and Urban Renewal: Section 112 and the New Haven Example. M.U.S. 109 p., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 199)
  - Nodelman Sheldon Arthur. Mino del Reame: An Exercise in Historical Epistemology. M.A. (HA) 106 p., 1959 (Box 12, Folder 200)
  - Northen Oscar Edwards Jr. An Analysis of Lower State Street: A Transitional Area between the Central Business District and a Residential Neighborhood. To Establish State Street's Place in New Haven's Future. M.C.P. 54 p., 1960 (Box 12, Folder 201)
  - Nubel, Herbert R. National Outdoor Advertising and the Preservation of the Cityscape. Vol. I & II. M.F.A. 137 p., 1956
    See: box 5, folders 11-12
  - Ockman Carol. Matisse's Bonheur de Vivre. M.A. (HA) 93 p., 1975 (Box 12, Folder 202)
  - Oliver Ray Steven. Landforms: The Use of Land as a Design Element in the Manipulation of the Environment. M.Arch. 155 p., 1971 (Box 12, Folder 203)
  - Omokhodion, Akuewanbhor. Sewage Development for Metropolitan Lagos, Nigeria. C.P. Thesis. 54 p., 1971 (Box 12, Folder 204)
  - Orr Christina. An Analysis of Elmwood, the Lockwood Mansion, by Detlef Lienau. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 113 p. (Vol. I, 2 copies), 1974 (Box 12, Folder 205-207)
  - Overby Osmund R. The Architecture of College Hill, 1770-1900, Residential Development in the Area of the Original Town of Providence, Rhode Island. Ph.D. 252 p., 1963 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Palladino Lora. The Adoration of the Magi: Eastern Magus and Western King in Fifteenth Century Florence. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 216 p., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 209-210)
  - Pancoast John E. Alberti's Vision of Movement. M.A. (HA) 26 p., 1950 (Box 12, Folder 211)
  - Paoletti John Thomas. Charleval: A Study of French Chateau Architecture of the 16th Century. M.A. (HA) 79 p., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Passanti Chiara. Benedetto Alfieri Architetto. In Lieu of Dept. Paper (HA) 174 p., 1970 (Box 13, Folder 213)
  - Peck Sara Graham. The Eclecticism of J. A. D. Ingres. M.A. 188 p., 1945 (Box 13, Folder 214)
  - Pendergast Carol L. (nee Stamatis). The Secular Sculpture of Cluny. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper (HA) 229 p., 1968 (Box 13, Folder 215-216)
  - Perlman Konrad Joseph. Method in Planning: An Analysis of the Methods and Techniques Used in Assessing Planning Areas. M.C.P. 114 p., 1960 (Box 13, Folder 217)
  - Poole Leslie. Thesis Metaphor. M.F.A., 1970
    See: Folio
  - Pospisil, Zdenka. Kwoma Sculpture: A Study of Form and Design. M.A. (HA) 161 p., 1964? (Box 13, Folder 218-219)
  - Post, Penelope. The Theme of Bathers in a Landscape in the Painting of Salvator Rosa. M.A. (HA) 113 p., 1967 (Box 13, Folder 220-221)
  - Price Charles. The Wood Engravings of Frederick Sandys: A Preliminary Study of Sources and Themes. M.A. (HA) 105 p., 1962 (Box 13, Folder 222)
  - Quick Michael A. Convention, Transformation, and Innovation in Ruben's Female Portrait Types. Dept. Paper (HA) 117 p., 1972 (Box 13, Folder 223)
  - Rao, Chalasani Nageswara. "An Approach to Regional Planning in Developing Areas": India as a Case Study. M.C.F. 48 p., 1960
    See: box 6, folder 14
  - Rauguin Virginia Chieffo. The San Diego Crucifixion Panel. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 117 p., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 224-225)
  - Richardson Douglas Scott. Christ Church Cathedral, Fredericton, New Brunswick. M.A. (HA) 127 p., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 226)
  - Riggs Timothy. L"Estampe Originale: A Late Nineteenth Century Publication of Original Prints. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 110 p., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 227-228)
  - Robb David M. Jr. Thomas Sully: The Business of Painting. M.A. (HA) 150 p., 1967 (Box 13, Folder 229-230)
  - Robb Francis Osborn. Mid-Nineteenth-Century Royal Portraiture in England and France. M.A. (HA) 177 p., 1968 (Box 14, Folder 231-232)
  - Robinson Duncan. Gertrude Stein: The Legend of a Collector. M.A. (HA) 71 p., 1967 (Box 14, Folder 233)
  - Roderiguez Oswaldo. Three Essays in the Art of Thomas Cole. Dept. Paper (HA) 66 p., 1975 (Box 14, Folder 234)
  - Romney Hervin A. R. A Study of Some Aspects of the Relation between Culture and the Dwelling with a View to Architectural Design Theory. M.E.D. 136 p., 1975 (Box 14, Folder 235)
  - Roscoe Lewis Scott. An Analysis of Residential Environment with Regard to Private Yards and Neighborhood Concepts. M.C.P. 142 p., 1961 (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - Roth Leland M. The Plan of the Acropolis: A Study of Its Topography and Development. Dept. Paper (HA) 71 p., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - Sagadencky Eugene. A Survey of Public Housing in the United States and A Project Rehabilitation Case Study. M.C.P. 107 p., 1961 (Box 14, Folder 238)
  - Saijo Hideo. Plan-type Study. M.E.D. 198 p., 1977 (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - Sandberg John. The Early Paintings of James Whistler 1834-1863. M. A. (HA) 111 p., 1962 (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - Sayre C. Franklin. Classical Elements of Sōtatsu's Art: His Scrolls and Screens. Dept. Paper Yale/University Tokyo. 86 p., 1974 (Box 14, Folder 241)
  - Schloss Christine Skeeles. Post-revolutionary portraiture in Southern New England: the Beardsley Limner and Ten contemporary artists. Dept Paper (HA) 98 p., 1972 (Box 14, Folder 242)
  - Sears Elizabeth L. An Illustrated Octave: Representations of the Beatitudes in Medieval Art. M.A. (HA) 191 p., 1976 (Box 14, Folder 243)
  - Seiberling Grace. Monet at Argenteuil. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 102 p., 1967 (Box 14, Folder 244-245)
  - Selig J. Daniel. Lemon Hill Mansion. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 103 p., 1962 (Box 14, Folder 246-247)
  - Shapiro Ellen R. Giuseppe Terragni: La Casa del Fascio di Como and the Fascist Aesthetic. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 108 p., 1976 (Box 14, Folder 248-249)
  - Shaprio Alexandra M. Perception, Scale, and Urban Architecture. M.C.P. 89 p., 1966 (Box 14, Folder 250)
  - Shiff Richard A. Color Relationships in Cézanne's Paintings. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper (HA) 117 p., 1968 (Box 15, Folder 251-252)
  - Silver Kenneth E. Classicism, Construction, and "La Grande Guerre". M.A. (HA) 84 p., 1975 (Box 15, Folder 253)
  - Simo Melanie. London and London: A Plan for the Growth of the Metropolis. Dept. Paper (HA) 93 p., 1973 (Box 15, Folder 254)
  - Simon Marcia Solomon. John Vanderlyn's Marius on the Ruins of Carthage. M.A. (HA) 101 p., 1963 (Box 15, Folder 255)
  - Slatkin Carole Anne. The Still-lifes of Emile Bernard and Paul Césanne 1884-1890. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper (HA) 87 p., 1968 (Box 15, Folder 256-257)
  - Small Mary Regina. Community Relations: The Implementation of Planning and Renewal Programs: New Haven Experience 1955-1958. M.C.P. 195 p. (Box 15, Folder 258)
  - Smith Janet G. David Scott R.S.A.: First Illustrator of Coleridge's Rime of the Ancient Mariner. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 154 p., 1966 (Box 15, Folder 259-261)
  - Smith Virginia. A Study of Three Private Printing Presses. M.F.A. 59 p., 1958
    See: box 7, folders 15-16
  - Spear John Kendall. Observations on the Development of a User-responsive Urban Housing Arche type. M.E.D. 84 p., 1975 (Box 15, Folder 262)